William N. Bonaparte

G-15 Alteza Street, Urb. Portal de las Cumbres · San Juan, PR 00926 787.525.4379(cel) · wnbonaparte@gmail.com

Seasoned Information Technology Leader with more than 20 years of experience in the Healthcare Insurance, Banking and Transaction Processing Industries. Latest achievement includes the Digital Transformation for Process and Projects with the implementation of Security Strategies for hybrid cloud environments to enhance the quality of service using artificial intelligence and machine learning solutions. Expert knowledge in the operation and maintenance of information and telecommunications systems. Skilled in the different phases of the IT Operations using the ITSM principles. Effective at building SLA oriented operational teams, focusing in metrics and quality of service offered. Customer oriented with the ability to initiate alliance with vendors and suppliers. Key core qualifications includes:

- IT Strategy & Business Integration
- Enterprise Architecture
- Security Strategies and Applications
- Policies & Procedures following HIPAA, SOX, PCI Regulations
- Team Leadership
- Employee Management and Development
- Performance Optimization & IT Gap Analysis
- Project Management / Change Management
- Service Desk, NOC & SOC Operations
- Data Center, Infrastructure & Security Operations
- Business Continuity / Disaster Recovery
- System Implementation
- CAPEX/OPEX Budget Recommendation & Analysis

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Medical Card System (MCS), San Juan PR

Senior Vice President

Information Technology (August 2017 to present)

Leader of the Company IT Department, focusing on the IT Transformation for projects quality and on time delivery. Develop a Security Strategy to minimize the risk associated to Account Provisioning, Patch Management and Systems Vulnerabilities. Implemented an Enterprise Initiative for security awareness with focus on cybersecurity, phishing and systems obsolescence. Serve as the IT Officer Liaison between Compliance and Legal Departments for Security Events and Incidents. Lead the Enterprise Project Management Office with more than 30 key business projects running simultaneously. Manage the OPEX (\$12MM) and CAPEX (\$4.5MM) budget for the Division.

Vice President

IT Solutions Delivery (August 2014 to July 2017)

Establish the IT direction of the Infrastructure and Software Development initiatives to drive the business strategy of MCS. Develop cloud strategy for operational efficiencies and cost reduction following best security practices. Manage telecommunications contracts for better services and less expenses. Lead the change for Service Oriented IT employee culture. Manage the Operational System Reliability and Disaster Recovery Plan.

Triple S Advantage Solutions Inc, Guaynabo PR

IT Director

Information Technology Division (September 2012 to July 2014)

Lead the IT Infrastructure and Security Group. Create, implement and fixed SOX and HIPAA Compliance policies and procedures for 29 GAP's. Enhance the Security Group Services with the creation of a SOC with the interaction with an external MSSP. Negotiate SLA's with internal and external providers to comply with Quality of Service and Service Delivery. Prepare and Manage the Capex and Opex budget (\$4MM)for the IT Division. Member of the Triple S - IT Operational Steering Committee.

EVERTEC, San Juan, PR

Assistant Vice President & Manager

Open System Department (June 2011 to August 2012)

Manage and support Windows/Unix servers for more than 1,500 physical and virtual servers. Develop and implemented new infrastructure following users and client's specifications. Maintain, modify and create backup policies in compliance with company's regulations. In charge of a team of two (2) managers, four (4) supervisores and sixty six (66) employees.

Network System Support Department (June 2009 to May 2011)

Manage the resources for first and second level support for the IT infrastructure consisted of 5,000 pc's, 1,100 windows server and a voice & data network for 7,000 users. Managed 7 direct supervisor and 95 employees at three locations in Puerto Rico and USVI. Report to the Technology System and Operations Division Manager.

- Responsible for the deployment of Antivirus, PC's/Windows Server patch security software upgrade.
- Provide IT support (PC's, Voice/Data Network) for five major Government Agencies
- Operational Owner of the Network Line of Business with a \$34 millions in revenue.

Transacta Event Operations (July 2007 to May 2009)

Responsible for the daily operations of the event creation, Transacta IT infrastructure & applications, outlet monitoring and Service Desk support. Direct the location movement of the Transacta Infrastructure from Miami to PR, in order to saved \$200,000 yearly in rented space. Managed 1 direct supervisor and 16 employees in Puerto Rico.

- Security administration for the admin & sales applications
- Incident and Problem Management
- Evaluate performance reports to provide feedback on enhancements for the web application

Network Operations Center (January 2004 to April 2007)

Direct 7x24 Network Operation Center with clients in the USA, Central & South America and the Caribbean. Responsible for the alert configuration of the server and network appliance in accordance with the OLA. Managed 2 direct supervisors and 20 employees.

- Prepared daily exceptions to alert Senior Management and clients.
- Service Monitoring of more than 4,000 assets including servers and communications equipment.
- Administer a \$100,000 monthly budget.

BANCO POPULAR DE PUERTO RICO, San Juan, PR

Manager

Network Processing and Control Center (January 2002 to December 2003)

Responsible for the batch operation processing applications including files transmission. Managed 4 direct supervisors and 45 employees.

- 7x24 Network and Scheduling operations area
- Support daily institutions files refresh
- Completes clients daily batch application process in accordance with SLA defined.

Operations Supervisor (January 2000 to December 2001)

Network Alert & Control Center

Responsible for the third shift creation in the Control Center in order to provide a 7x24 environment. Managed 12 employees.

- In charge of the lines and server monitoring & alert systems
- Create monthly rotation schedules to provide 7x24 support

Network Engineer (July 1997 to December 1999)

Network Department

- Design and Prepared telecommunications diagrams for the development of new projects or network enhancements.
- Design and Implement the first phase of the BPPR Private Digital Microwave Network.
- Develop test plan and equipment rollout for Y2K project.

Universidad Interamericana, Bayamon, PR

Professor (2001-2002)

Electrical and Computer Engineer Department

- Math and Basic Microprocessor Information Lessons
- Prepared twice a week class with laboratory

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Science Electrical Engineer · University of Puerto Rico · Mayaguez, PR

PROFESSIONAL ENRICHMENT

IEEE Computer Society · Chairman Puerto Rico & Caribe Section (2008-2009)

IEEE · President Puerto Rico & Caribe Section (2006-2007) · Vice President Puerto Rico & Caribe Section (2004-2005)

IEEE Communications Society · Chairman Puerto Rico & Caribe Section (2002-2003)

SIEPR \cdot Directive Member and Secretary (1998-2000)